

MOHAMMED RISHAD V K

Senior Software Engineer (Python, Django, Flask, Postgres, RestAPI, AWS, Docker)

More than 5 years of experience working with Scalable, Reusable, Reliable, Object Oriented Programming(OOP), Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) in Software Development. I'm a quick learner and highly flexible to adapt to new challenges, take ownership, handle multiple responsibilities and mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer, StudySmarter UG

MUNICH, GERMANY (REMOTE FROM INDIA)

Dec 2021 - Present

- Taking ownership for the development and maintaining different learning modes like Practice, Quiz, Spaced Repetition, Type to answer, etc.
- Improvising and adding new feature to core product like Flashcards,
 Documents, Summary, Textbook, Exercises, etc.
- Collaborating with team and cross functional team to achieve common goals.
- Writing unittest, integration, functional, etc to make sure quality of the product.
- Peer code review with cross functional teams.
- Technologies
 - Python, Django, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, RestAPI, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, CloudFront, Sentry, CloudWatch, EC2, EKS, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Senior Software Engineer, Reckonsys Tech Labs Pvt. Ltd

BENGALURU, KARNATAKA, INDIA

May 2019 - Nov 2021

- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the business to implement features and understand use cases (US, Europe, India).
- Contribute to design and development of Backend and API's using Monolith and Microservice Architecture.
- Contribute to the technical design and development APIs with performance and scalability in mind.
- Research, suggest and implement new solutions in performance of backend service.
- Integration of third-party API's and creating webhooks for the business.
- Experience with devops and infrastructure practices and technology like CI, deployment automation, provisioning, Amazon AWS.
- Mentoring and training new joinees and juniors.
- Some industries worked are Hotel, Sports, Hiring, Transport, Aviation, Healthcare, Analytics, Travel, etc.
- Technologies

Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS,
 GraphQL, RestAPI, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Elixir / Phoenix,

Malappuram, Kerala India, 676510 +91(0)9567802281 mohammedrishad.vk@gmail.com

LINKS

- Website
- LinkedIn
- Github
- StackOverflow

SKILLS

Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, GraphQL, RestAPI, CSS,, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, HTML, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Git, AWS, GCP, PyTest, Unittest, Linux(Ubuntu), Unix, Jira, Agile

Familiar:

Kubernetes, SQLAlchemy, Elixir, Phoenix, Node.js, Express JS, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, XML, JSON, Elastic Search, Numpy, Pandas, Mac OS, Windows, Terraform, Kafka, Data Structures, Algorithms

AWARDS & HONORS

SayOne Rockstar – Best Performer (Dec 2018).

Winner Djangothon2018 by HackerEarth (1st Prize Winner).

Acknowledged by Google, Microsoft, Sony, Freelancer, Kaspersky, eBay, CRIS, etc. for reporting security bugs.

LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient, C1)
- German (Beginner, A1)
- Malayalam (Native, C2)

Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, SES, CloudFront, IAM, Lambda, EC2, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Clients

 NuFlights, ClipHire, Pharmallama, TransportSimple,, Acumen Aviation, Kiplist, D8aDriven, Moonllight, Vigna World

Software Engineer, SayOne Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA

Feb 2018 - May 2019

- Help to develop 5+ web applications from scratch.
- Managed team of 4 members including Backend and Frontend Developers.
- Developed a highly scalable ecommerce SaaS platform for independent pet retailers with Django and Postgres. (Worked on DB Design, Dashboard(Role, Orders, Invoicing, Products, Theming, Coupon, Offers) and Frontend Pages, etc)
- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the client to implement features and understand use cases.
- Developed and maintained an article website for big data, blockchain, and artificial intelligence having insights and jobs..

Technologies

Python / Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 TypeScript, Angular, Celery, Redis, Elastic Search, RestAPI, Git,
 SendGrid, Kafka

Clients

o <u>eTailPet</u>, <u>FeedMyFurBaby</u>, <u>Datafloq</u>, <u>Mavin</u>, <u>BeCo</u>, <u>ProteinForPets</u>,

Python Developer, CogniCor Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA

Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

- Involved in the development and maintaining of Chatbot and Dashboard using Python 2.7, Django 1.8, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, MongoDB.
- Build Analytics Dashboard to help the clients to analyze/visualize chats and leads.
- Created periodic bank account statements for Federal Bank.
- Closely worked with banks and Insurance companies to collect chatbot requirements.

Technologies

o Python, Django, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Git

Clients

o ICICI Bank, OCBC Bank, Federal Bank, Tata Capital, Atos.

EDUCATION

University of Calicut — M.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA

2014 - 2016

- Blue Card Eligible EU / German
- Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 7.13/10 (71.3%) A grade

University of Calicut — B.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA

2011 - 2014

Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 2.76/4 (69 %) - B grade

INTERESTS

- Open Source Contribution
- Competitive Programming
- Web Security Research
- Mentoring
- Continuous Learning
- Photography
- Travel
- Football (Soccer)